<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Fedora | blog:donri]]></title>
  <link href="http://dag.github.com/blog/categories/fedora/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dag.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-03T23:08:53+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://dag.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Dag Odenhall]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[dag.odenhall@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing Images to Flash Drives]]></title>
    <link href="http://dag.github.com/blog/2012/08/03/writing-images-to-flash-drives/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-03T22:36:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dag.github.com/blog/2012/08/03/writing-images-to-flash-drives</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It seems odd that there are no obvious ways to write a disk image to a USB
flash drive from a Linux system, when there are so many options for burning
images to a CD.  I often find myself wanting to run a "Live CD" and using a
flash drive instead is both faster and less wasteful.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So we have to resort to low-level tools like <code>dd</code>:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo dd if=Fedora-17-x86_64-Live-Desktop.iso of=/dev/sdh bs=8M conv=fsync
</code></pre>

<p>This is assuming your USB flash drive is the <code>/dev/sdh</code> device; you can
find out with <code>dmesg</code> or a tool like GNOME's "Disks" utility.</p>

<p>So this works, but there's not a whole lot of feedback.  The <code>dd</code> program
is like that.  The man page suggests we can get it to print some statistics
by sending the USR1 signal to it.  Hokay.  Need to open a new terminal for
this!</p>

<pre><code>$ pkill -USR1 ^dd$
</code></pre>

<p>Cool!  But wouldn't it be nice if <code>dd</code> had a progress bar or somesuch,
without requiring a new terminal just to get some feedback?  Enter <code>pv</code>.</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo yum install pv
$ pv Fedora-17-x86_64-Live-Desktop.iso | sudo dd of=/dev/sdh bs=8M conv=fsync
</code></pre>

<p>Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GHC 7.4 on Fedora 17]]></title>
    <link href="http://dag.github.com/blog/2012/07/24/latest-haskell-platform-on-fedora-17/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-24T16:28:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://dag.github.com/blog/2012/07/24/latest-haskell-platform-on-fedora-17</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fedora 17 ships the previous release of the Haskell Platform and GHC 7.0.4.
To get the latest platform and GHC 7.4.1 you can install from the "rawhide"
repository.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First make sure to install the packages you want from your
normal repositories so as to avoid pulling a lot of dependencies from
rawhide:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo yum install haskell-platform
</code></pre>

<p>You may substitute <code>haskell-platform</code> for <code>ghc</code> if you don't want the whole
platform.  Next we install the repository description for rawhide.  It will
be a disabled repository by default so we enable it temporarily and update
the packages we want:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo yum install fedora-release-rawhide
$ sudo yum --enablerepo rawhide update haskell-platform
</code></pre>

<p>This "rawhide" repository is what will eventually become Fedora 18.  If you
use the commands above it will be enabled temporarily for the duration of
that "yum install", but your system will be otherwise unaffected.</p>

<p>Should you regret what you have done you can easily revert the
installation:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo yum distro-sync
</code></pre>

<p>This will synchronize all your installed packages to the versions available
in your <em>enabled</em> repositories.  If this fails you might try removing all
the haskell packages first:</p>

<pre><code>$ sudo yum remove haskell-platform 'ghc-*'
</code></pre>

<p><em>Updated in accordance with recommendations from juhp; see comments below.
Also updated with improved recovery method.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
